（黒子(くろこ)）うっ！
（葉山(はやま)）あっ
（小金井(こがねい)）えい ふっ！
Rakuzan
Seirin
We got them back, but...
（土田(つちだ)）堅実に返した けど…
（伊月(いづき)）今 ウチには
シューターがいない
We don't have any shooters.
スリーを打つだけなら
火神(かがみ) コガ オレにもできるが—
Kagami, Koga and I can shoot threes.
But we've got nowhere near Hyuga's accuracy.
成功率は
日向(ひゅうが)に遠く及ばない
（木吉(きよし)）洛山(さくざん)には赤司(あかし)以上に
怖いシューターがいる
Rakuzan has scarier shooters than Akashi.
Mibuchi!
Is this...
（根武谷(ねぶや)）まさかこれは！
Wild instincts?
（実渕）野生？
（若松(わかまつ)）
ノーフェイクでスリー!?
A three without a fake?
（桜井(さくらい)）いや これは…
No, this is...
（桜井）“虚空”！
Void!
（葉山）レオ姉の“虚空”に
飛びついた!?
He jumped during Leo's Void?
The rebound's mine!
（根武谷）オイ！
（ホイッスル）
（小金井）ううっ くっそー
Damn.
Thanks to Koga, I know how
to stop his three pointers.
（日向）コガのおかげで
３種のシュートの攻略法…
そして 見切ったぜ—
And how to beat Void!
“虚空”！
Let Me Warn You
Hyuga, you're coming in?
（伊月）日向… 出るのか!?
Yeah. I know the risks.
ああ リスクは百も承知だ
それでも 今度こそ
実渕はオレが倒す！
But this time I'll beat Mibuchi.
Sorry, Hyuga. I wasn't strong enough.
ワリィ 日向
オレの力不足で…
What are you talking about?
（日向）何言ってんだよ
You're the reason I can fight.
コガのおかげで
オレも戦えんだ
I'll crush him for you, too.
オマエの分まで—
ギャフンと
言わせてきてやるよ！
Yeah. I'm counting on you, Hyuga.
おう 任せた！
頼むよ 日向！
（白金(しろがね)）あと10分だ
We have ten more minutes.
慌てることはない
There's no need to rush.
But don't try to maintain the point gap.
だが 今の点差を
守ろうと思うな
Keep attacking until the
end and crush Seirin!
最後まで攻めて
誠凛(せいりん)をたたき潰してこい！
（洛山選手たち）おう！
Yeah!
Leo,
they're putting Hyuga back in.
向こうは
日向が出てくるようだ
He may have four fouls,
but don't let down your guard.
だが ４ファウルでも
決して油断するな
I know.
Eikichi, there's still
life in Kiyoshi's eyes.
（赤司）永吉(えいきち)… 木吉の目は
まだ死んでいない
Pull yourself together.
気を引き締めろ
おう！
Yeah.
小太郎(こたろう) いつまで
おとなしくしているつもりだ？
Kotaro, how long are you going
to stay out of the fight?
まだ点を取ってもらうぞ
You need to score again.
Of course.
当然！
And I'm supposed to keep playing like this.
（黛(まゆずみ)）そんでオレも
このまま出ろってかい？
使える間は
出がらしになるまで使うなんて—
How economical of you to use
me until I've got nothing left.
随分と倹約家じゃねーの？
お坊ちゃん
But...
だが…
はっきりとは分からないが—
I'm not sure what it is.
But something seems off about Akashi.
今の赤司には
何か違和感を覚える
（アナウンス）
インターバル終了です
The break is now over.
Let's go!
（日向）よし いくぞ！
（木吉）ん…
Teppei?
あ？ どうした？ リコ
What's up, Riko?
Nothing. Never mind.
（リコ）ううん… 何でもない
Kiyoshi!
（日向）木吉！
Yeah.
絶対勝つぞぉ！
Let's win!
Seirin, fight!
誠凛！ ファイッ！
（誠凛一同）オォォー！
Yeah!
It's finally the fourth quarter.
（笠松(かさまつ)）
いよいよ第４クオーターか
This will determine the
Winter Cup championship.
これでウインターカップの
覇者が決まる
（森山(もりやま)）誠凛は
20点差を巻き返せるか？
Can Seirin make up a 20 point difference?
Who knows?
さぁな
But they haven't given up.
でも あいつらは諦めてねぇ
When it comes to killing giants,
attitude matters more than strategy.
ジャイアントキリングに
一番大事なのは—
戦略以上に まず気持ちだ
A three already?
いきなりスリー!?
あっ！ チェックも速い
He's already on him!
（日向）カントク
１つ頼みがあるんだ
Coach, will you do me a favor?
What?
Can you stop my hands from shaking?
この手の震え
何とかしてくんねぇ？
Wait, what?
今 バシッと
声出ししてなかった？
But you sounded so in control.
That's irrelevant.
それと これとは別の話じゃ！
オレ ４ファウルだぞ!?
I've got four fouls.
The pressure's killing me.
プレッシャー ハンパねぇ！
はぁ… ったくもー
Sheesh. Turn around!
後ろ！
Okay!
な… は はい！
WHACK
Ow!
だあああ！ イッテエ！
（実渕）速い！
He's fast.
（１年生たち）
よっしゃー！ キャプテン！
Yeah!
Nice, Captain!
Rakuzan
Seirin
しゃー！ いくぜ 洛山！
Yes! Let's go, Rakuzan!
（実渕）４ファウルで—
With four fouls, I thought
he'd barely be able to play.
かろうじてプレーするのが
やっとかと思ったけど…
But this is the best he's played all game.
まさか ここで
この試合一番のキレとはね
よぉし １本止めんぞ！
Let's stop their attack!
Yeah!
（誠凛選手たち）おう！
Defense! Defense!
（誠凛部員たち）ディーフェンス！
ディーフェンス！
Defense! Defense!
Their defense is good.
（宮地(みやじ)）いいディフェンスだ
Hyuga really pulls his team together.
やっぱり日向が入ると
チームがグッと引き締まる
だが １つもファウルを
許されねぇ状態で どう戦う？
But how can he fight when he
can't afford a single foul?
You can do it, Junpei.
（リコ）頑張れ 順平(じゅんぺい)！
That's Heaven!
あれは“天”のシュート！
But Hyuga knows it's coming!
（土田）だが 日向も読んでる！
フェイク!?
A fake? Then he's going for...
じゃあ 本命は
“地”のシュート！
Earth! Hyuga-san's fifth foul!
日向さんの５ファウル！
Captain!
キャプテン！
（実渕）跳んでない!?
He's not jumping.
まさかこれも 読まれた？
Did he predict this, too?
Mibuchi, your form is practically
identical before you
（日向）実渕
オマエの３種のシュートには—
jump for each of your shots.
跳ぶ直前まで
フォームに違いはない
だが 重心の位置が
わずかに違う！
But your center of gravity
is slightly different.
Heaven, Earth, Void.
“天”“地”“虚空”
それぞれ跳ぶ方向に
重心が一瞬 動く
Your center of gravity shifts towards
the direction you're jumping.
As long as I know which way...
それさえ見抜ければ…
Go, Hyuga!
いけー 日向ー！
Hyuga!
日向！
This is the strongest he's been all game!
（根武谷）ここまでで
一番の馬力じゃねえか！
鉄平！ まさか…
Teppei, are you...
That idiot!
あのバカ…
うぐ… ぐうううっ…！
I can't make the right call about
my future or injury anymore.
（木吉）先とかケガとか—
もう正しいだけの判断
できっこない
今 この瞬間が…
All that matters is this moment.
うおぉぉぉぉ！ ぐおおお！
ダメだ
それでもポジションが取れない
It's no use. He still can't get in position.
（日向）
そんなこったろーと思ったよ
I thought that might be it.
No matter what we say,
you're always reckless.
どんだけ言っても
オマエは無茶しちまう
Even if we subbed you out,
you'd force your way back on the court.
無理矢理 引っ込めても
リコを泣かせて出てきちまう
もう止めねーよ
I won't stop you anymore.
木吉テメー
Kiyoshi, how long have you been a center?
何年 センターやってんだ！
んな筋肉バカに
負けてんじゃねぇ！
Don't let that musclebound moron beat you!
くうっ！
（根武谷）速(はえ)ぇ！
He's fast.
うぐっ… うおおお！
Go!
いっけー！
Kagami!
火神！
（１年生たち）よっしゃー！
Yeah!
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
Now you've done it, Junpei-chan.
（実渕）やってくれたわね
順平ちゃん
マジで潰すわ
I'll crush you.
Right back at you.
こっちのセリフだ
And stop calling me that!
それと“ちゃん”付けで
下の名前 呼ぶな！
（葉山）キレてっけど
冷静さは失ってない
He's mad, but he hasn't lost his cool.
さすが レオ姉は心配ねーか
I don't need to worry about Leo.
それより…
But...
（根武谷）チィッ！ クソがっ！
Damn it!
落ち着けよ 永(えい)ちゃん
Calm down, Ei-chan.
What are you doing, Kotaro?
何すんだ 小太郎！
オレと同じで
カッとなりやすいんだから
You've got a short fuse like me. Be careful.
気をつけろよ
Kiyoshi's strong.
木吉は強(つえ)え
ケガがなけりゃ 少し前まで
オレらと同格だったヤツだぞ
If not for his injury,
he would've been as strong as us.
間違っても ナメんなよ
Don't underestimate him.
（根武谷）チッ うっせーな
Shut up. I know.
分かってるっつーんだよ
（観客）うおお 何度目だ？
シューティングガード対決!?
Another shooting guard showdown!
（実渕）日向順平…
こいつは危険だわ
Hyuga Junpei...
He's dangerous.
アタシの３種のシュートを
見分けて反応してくる
He can distinguish between my
three shots and react accordingly.
ならば その中でも—
Then I'll use Void,
unstoppable even if you see it coming.
分かっていても
止められない“虚空”で勝負
But maybe he's figured
something out about Void.
でも“虚空”に対しても
何かつかんでいるかもしれない
スリー以外で勝負か？
ボールを回すか…
Should I avoid threes or pass the ball?
No, that's why I must fight!
いいえ だからこそ勝負！
A Rakuzan player can't back down.
洛山選手としても
引くわけにはいかない
I'll risk all my pride and shoot Void!
アタシのプライド すべてを懸けて
“虚空”を打つ！
（氷室(ひむろ)）そうか！ 分かったぞ
That's it!
ディフェンスが
あのシュートのブロックに—
I know why the defender can't
jump when he takes that shot.
跳べなくなる秘密…
It's because of how deep he
crouches before he jumps.
跳ぶ直前に沈み込む深さだ！
実渕は“虚空”を打つ際—
When Mibuchi shoots Void,
he crouches lower than normal.
通常のシュートより
深く沈み込んでいる
And when he jumps,
そして 跳ぶとき—
ディフェンスの膝が伸び切った瞬間
わざと動きを止める
he stops moving just as the defender's
knees are fully extended.
その 一瞬に
つられたディフェンスは—
The defender expends all the power of
his crouch, leaving him unable to jump.
沈んだ分の力が逃げてしまい—
もう 跳ぶことができない
だが 実渕は深く沈んだ分
余力が残っている
But Mibuchi still has strength
from crouching so low.
He uses the remaining power to shoot.
その残った力で
シュートを打つ
That's the secret behind Void.
これが“虚空”の正体！
（日向）あー 背中いってえ…
My back hurts...
Has Riko always been that strong?
リコ あんな力 強かったか？
No, of course not.
…って んなわけねーか
きっと
そんだけ込めたんだろう
She just hit me extra hard.
With not just her own,
but the entire team's hopes.
あいつだけじゃなく
チーム全員分の思いを！
I don't care if you're an
Uncrowned King or Rakuzan!
五将だろーが
洛山だろーが知らねえよ！
どれだけ
オマエが強くても—
No matter how strong you
are, I'll stop this shot!
このシュートだけは
絶対 止めてやる！
うおあああああ！
Yes!
（リコ）やったー！
（小金井）日向ー！
Hyuga!
洛山ディフェンスを
切り裂いた！
They broke Rakuzan's defense!
（緑間(みどりま)）シューターの復活で
ディフェンスが外に広がり—
With the return of their shooter,
their defense spread out,
making it easier to create
space on the inside.
中にスペースが
できやすくなったか
させるかぁ！
No you don't!
あれに追いつくなんて…
How did he reach that?
（今吉(いまよし)）だが 後手
主導権は木吉や
But he's too late. Kiyoshi's in control.
スリー!?
A three?
It's a good shot.
いいループなのだよ
スピンもブレがない
There's no spin or shift.
（１年生たち）
うわぁぁー！ ３連続得点！
Three shots in a row!
But Akashi isn't saying anything.
（薫）…にしても
赤司は何も言わないな
何を考えている？
What is he thinking?
It's strange that he's emphasizing
one-on-ones with those three.
攻撃パターンが—
実渕たちのワンオンワンに
偏重なのも気にかかる
なぜ 自分で決めない？
Why doesn't he attack himself?
（黛）まさか…
Could it be?
（黛）今 こいつの前では—
Is he preventing even Akashi from attacking?
赤司ですら
そうせざるをえないのか…
（根武谷）
つうか どうなってやがる…
What's going on?
火神のすごみが
増してきてねーか？
Kagami's becoming even more impressive.
（赤司）今日 行われた
誠凛 対 桐皇(とうおう)の試合…
Today's Seirin-Touou game was
面白い
interesting.
正直 あの発想はなかったな
Honestly, that hadn't occurred to me.
I have experience with the Zone.
ゾーンは僕も経験がある
But what's truly surprising is how
Daiki deliberately entered it.
だが 驚くべきは—
大輝(だいき)が自らの力で
意図的に入ったことだ
It's possible
（赤司）可能だ
with sufficient focus to push open the door
扉を開ける腕力となるだけの
集中力
そして 扉の鍵となる—
and awareness of your own
trigger to unlock it.
自分にとっての
トリガーを自覚できれば…
Sei-chan, there you are.
（実渕）あら 征(せい)ちゃん
ここにいたの？
Yeah.
ああ どうした？
What is it?
（根武谷）明日は
ようやく試合だからな
We've got a game tomorrow.
軽く体 動かしとこうと
思ってよ
We wanted to get a light workout.
It sucks that we haven't played since
the first day since we're the top seed.
ウインターカップ 始まっても—
シード校は初日 試合なくて
つまんないよね
（赤司）ならば ちょうどいい
I'm glad you're here. I need an opponent.
少し 相手を頼む
いいよ！
何？ ワンオンワン？
Sure. What do you want, a one-on-one?
（赤司）いいや ３対１だ
No. Three-on-one.
Huh? Hey, Akashi.
んん？ おい 赤司
I'm pretty sure you can't beat us.
いくらなんでも それは
負ける気がしないんだけど？
どうなっても知んねーよ？
Don't complain about the results.
Good. This should work in an actual game.
よし これならば
実戦も問題ないだろう
（根武谷たち）ハァ ハァ ハァ…
Seriously?
マジ… かよ…
化け物すぎっしょ… 赤司
Akashi's a monster.
But we should consider this my trump card.
（赤司）だが これは
切り札と呼ぶべきものだ
Using this would mean Rakuzan
is in a dangerous situation.
これを出すということは
すなわち—
状況が洛山にとって
危険であることを意味する
そして もう１つ
And one more thing.
これは忠告だ
Let me warn you.
My trigger for entering this condition is...
この状態になるトリガーは…
They're using a stealth
full-court man-to-man defense.
（根武谷）
クソッ ここできたか！
ステルス･オールコート
マンツーマンディフェンス！
（葉山）ぐうっ！
（葉山）ヤバイっしょ これは！
This can't be good.
ゾーンに入った火神の
ディフェンスエリアを考えると—
Considering the range of
Kagami's defense in the Zone,
黒子に捕まらない
パスコースなんて ほぼない！
there's hardly any passes Kuroko can't steal.
（葉山）レオ姉！
Leo!
Crap!
（実渕）しまっ…
（葉山）ぐっ…
Kuroko!
黒子！
止まった！
He stopped.
木吉さんがすべてを懸けても
根武谷さんのパワーには勝てない…
Even at full power,
Kiyoshi-san can't beat Nebuya-san.
勝てなくてもええんや
He doesn't have to win.
競えるだけの力があればこそ
駆け引きが生きる
He just needs enough to
compete to stay in the game.
He put pressure on his leg to spin again!
（根武谷）こいつ
足に負担のでかいスピンを また…
おおおおーりゃー！
We're ten points behind!
10点差！
Rakuzan
Seirin
Damn.
クソッ
Mibuchi, the four of you will
go during our next attack.
実渕
次の攻撃だけ
オマエたち４人で攻めろ
What? Sei-chan, what do you—
征ちゃん
それってどういう… はっ！
Run.
（赤司）走れ
（葉山）えい！
They broke through in a second.
一気に中盤まで突破された！
Crap! Go back!
まずい 戻れ！ あ…
（伊月）自陣から動かない？
He's not moving?
Think later! Focus on defense!
考えるのは後だ！
ディフェンス集中しろ！
He has the same eyes...
（実渕）
あの目は あのときと同じ…
Let me warn you.
（赤司）これは忠告だ
この状態になるトリガーは 勝利
My trigger for entering this condition
is the intent to achieve victory
人を動かすことに
よってではなく—
not by using others,
but by taking it for myself.
自分が動くことによって
必ず もぎ取るという意志だ
In other words,
つまり 僕が己の力のみで戦うと
決めたとき
when I fight with my strength alone.
When I lose hope in and abandon you.
オマエたちに失望し
見限ったときだ
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
まさか来るのか？ ５連続！
Are they going to score again?
（火神）決める！
I'll make the shot.
He can't stop my Meteor Jam
like he did in the first half.
このシチュエーションなら—
前半のメテオジャム破りは
使えねーはずだ！
Take this, Akashi!
（火神）食らえ 赤司！
あ… 赤司君…
Akashi-kun?
（赤司）
身分の違いを教えてやろう
I will demonstrate my superiority
to everyone here.
（赤司）
この場にいる者 すべてに…
Akashi's Zone.
（青峰(あおみね)）赤司のゾーン…
（火神）てやっ！
待ちやがれ 赤司！
Wait, Akashi!
そんな…
No way!
Stop him!
止めろー！
（日向）なんて緩急…
He changes speed so quickly!
He's too fast!
（伊月）速すぎる…
You have defied me.
ここまで僕に
歯向かったんだ
It's not enough for you to sit.
ただ座り込むだけでは
足りないな
ひざまずけ
Kneel.
（木吉）しまった…
Damn! A fake!
（木吉）フェイク！
そのまま たたえる姿で思い知れ
Witness my sublime form and realize
your defeat is absolute.
オマエたちの敗北は絶対だ
（ホイッスル）
（観客１）決めた！
He made it!
（観客２）ゴールからゴールまで
１人で持ってっちまった！
He took the ball from hoop to hoop!
Even without us...
（黛）味方を使うのをやめても…
いや やめたほうが強いとか
No, he's stronger without us.
オレらの存在意義もグラつく
化け物ぶりだろう！
Such a monster shakes our very existence.
Does he really not need us?
いや… マジで
必要としていないのか？
They called for a time out.
（緑間）タイムアウトを取ったか
But is there anything
they can do to stop him?
だが 取ったところで
止める手だてなどあるのか？
（火神）オレがやる… です
I'll do it.
Kagami! You mean you'll do it by yourself?
（降旗(ふりはた)）ちょっ… 火神！
まさか それって
１人でってこと？
おう んじゃ頼んだわ
We're counting on you, then.
What? Don't you think you
agreed too quickly, Captain?
（福田(ふくだ)）ええっ!?
なんか軽くないですか キャプテン
うん 妥当だとー思うよ
キタコレ！
It's a valid verdict. Yeah, nice.
You, too, Izuki-senpai?
伊月先輩も!?
You heard them, Kiyoshi.
だってさ 木吉
Okay.
分かった
ていうか みんな軽い！
Why is everyone agreeing?
Why are you objecting?
むしろ 何ツッコンでんだ？
What?
今までも ずっと
そうだったじゃねぇか
It's how we've always played.
Against the Generation of Miracles,
we always face this situation.
“キセキの世代”とやるなら
こういう局面は必ず来る
エースに
託さなきゃならねぇときが
Eventually we have to rely on our ace.
If we didn't have one, we'd be screwed.
託せるエースがいなかったら
お手上げかもしれない
But we have Kagami.
だが ウチには火神がいる
That's good enough.
そんで十分だろ？
Kagami-kun.
火神君…
You know what this means, Kagami-kun.
（リコ）
分かってるわね？ 火神君
This fight will determine
who wins and who loses.
ここからは勝つか負けるか
正真正銘のガチンコ勝負よ
Win, Kagami!
勝て！ 火神！
（河原(かわはら)･土田）あはっ
Yeah!
青峰
ひとつ気になっとったんやが…
Aomine, I've been wondering.
What?
Earlier you said something.
さっき言うとったやろ？
He's even deeper in the Zone.
（青峰）あの野郎
ゾーンが深くなってやがる
What did you mean?
あれは 一体
どういう意味や？
うん…
あくまでイメージの話だ
It's a metaphor.
ゾーンに入るとき
でかい扉を開ける
When you enter the Zone,
you open a massive door.
Inside it is water.
開けると水の中にいて—
集中力が増すほど
深く沈んでいく
The more you focus, the deeper you sink.
If you sink far enough, you reach the bottom.
そのまま沈んでいくと
底に着く
それがゾーンに入りきった状態
That's when you're fully
immersed in the Zone.
自分のパフォーマンスを
余さず すべて引き出せる
You can perform at your true best.
だが 更に もう１つ
でかい門があって—
But there's an even bigger door.
その扉の前には
顔の見えない誰かが立っている
A faceless figure stands
before it like a gatekeeper.
門番のように
What if you open that door?
（桜井）じゃあ もし
その扉を開けたら…
さあな
オレも その扉は開けたことはねぇ
Who knows?
I've never opened it.
だが 確信はある
But I'm certain.
その扉の先は
ゾーンを越えたゾーン
Beyond that door lies a
Zone greater than the Zone.
If Kagami has any chance of winning,
it's by opening the second door.
火神が赤司に
勝つ可能性があるとすれば—
第２の扉を開けることだ
Preview
（赤司）
勝負をエースに託したか？ 誠凛
You've entrusted your ace
with the game, Seirin?
Then I must simply shatter your hope.
ならば
その希望を打ち砕くのみ
I can't lose.
僕が負けることなど
ありえない
The weak must kneel before the strong.
Why Don't You Give Up
弱者は強者の前に ひれ伏せ
絶対は僕だ
I am absolute.